WHEN TIMES SQUARE WAS FULL OF INDIANS...LITTLE OLD NEW YORK WAS FULL OF FUN!
Knickerbocker Holiday is a music, comedy, history
film directed by Harry Joe Brown.
The wild and woolly early days of New York -- when it was still known as New
Amsterdam -- provide the backdrop for this period musical-comedy.
In 1650, Peter Stuyvesant arrives in New Amsterdam
to assume his duties as governor.
Stuyvesant is hardly the fun-loving type, and one of his first official acts is to call for the death of Brom
Broeck, a newspaper publisher well-known for his fearless exposes of police and government corruption.
However, Broeck hasn't done anything that would justify the death penalty, so
Stuyvesant waits (without much patience) for Broeck to step out of line.
Broeck is romancing a beautiful woman named Tina Tienhoven, whose
sister Ulda happens to be dating his best friend, Ten Pin.
After Stuyvesant's men toss Broeck in jail on a trumped-up charge,
Stuyvesant sets his sights on winning Tina's affections.
Brom Broeck, played by Nelson Eddy.
Peter Stuyvesant, played by Charles Coburn.
Tina Tienhoven, played by Constance Dowling.
Tienhoven, played by Ernest Cossart.
Ulda Tienhoven, played by Shelley Winters.
Tenpin, played by Johnnie Davis.
Knickerbocker Holiday is a 1944 American musical film directed by Harry Joe Brown
and starring Nelson Eddy, Charles Coburn and Constance Dowling.
It is based on the musical play of the same title set in
the 17th century colony of New Amsterdam.
The film's sets were designed by the art director Bernard Herzbrun.
The music by Werner R.
Heymann was nominated for an Oscar for best motion picture score.
The film explores themes of resistance, musical, based on
play or musical, historical, city council.
The tone is lighthearted.